Guide to the Human Rights Watch Records: Helsinki Watch,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Cathy Fitzpatrick Files, 1968-1993
  - Subseries III.2: Country Files
    - USSR
      - Yugoslavia
        - Salaj, Branko: Correspondence, 1981-1982 (Box 76, Folder 12)
        - Samouprava (Self-Management) (publication), 1986-1988 (Box 76, Folder 13)
        - Secret service, 1978-1985 (Box 76, Folder 14)
        - Sekelj, Laslo, 1983 (Box 77, Folder 1)
        - Seks, Vladimir
          - General, 1983-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 2-3)
          - Petition on his behalf, 1985 (Box 77, Folder 4)
        - Selic, Momcilo, 1979-1985, 1987, (2 Folders) (Box 77, Folder 5-6)
        - Seselj, Vojislav, 1984-1987 (Box 77, Folder 7)
        - Security, 1984 (Box 77, Folder 8)
        - SKUP (ublication) 1981-1986 (Box 77, Folder 9)
        - Slapsak Committee, 1987 (Box 77, Folder 10)
        - Slovenia
          - General, 1984-1989 (Box 77, Folder 11)
          - Army, 1988 (Box 78, Folder 1)
          - Independent Voices (publication), 1988-1989 (Box 78, Folder 2)
          - Mladina (youth magazine), 1987-1988 (Box 78, Folder 3)
        - Slovenian arrests (Jansa, Tasic, Borstner), 1988 (Box 78, Folder 4)
        - Solidarity--Yugoslavia, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 5)
        - Sunic, Tomislav, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 6)
        - Svaruna, 1987 (Box 78, Folder 7)
        - Terrorism, 1980-1987 (Box 78, Folder 8)
        - That’s Yugoslavia (publication), 1982-1988 (Box 78, Folder 9)
        - Travel, 1981-1984 (Box 78, Folder 10)
        - Trial documents, 1983-1986 (Box 78, Folder 11)
        - Trials, 1981-1988 (Box 78, Folder 12)
        - Tudjman, Franjo, 1981-1984 (Box 79, Folder 1)
        - USSR: Yugo-Soviet relations, 1978-1988 (Box 79, Folder 2)
        - United Nations, 1983 (Box 79, Folder 3)
        - UNESCO, 1986 (Box 79, Folder 4)
        - United States
          - Administration, 1988 (Box 79, Folder 5)
          - Congress
          - General, 1984-1987 (Box 79, Folder 6)
          - Correspondence, 1980-1982 (Box 79, Folder 7)
          - Presidential correspondence, 1980-1985 (Box 79, Folder 8)
          - State Department
            - General, 1982-1985 (Box 79, Folder 9)
            - Correspondence, 1980-1989 (Box 79, Folder 10)
            - Reports, 1980-1987 (Box 79, Folder 11)
        - Unrest, 1988-1989 (Box 79, Folder 12)
        - War criminals--WW II, 1986 (Box 79, Folder 14)
        - Workers, 1980-1988 (Box 79, Folder 15)
        - Writers, 1984-1988 (Box 79, Folder 16)
        - Yugoslav Helsinki Committee, 1987-1988 (Box 79, Folder 17)
        - Miscellaneous
          - Yugoslav mailing list: CADDY, 1980-1982 (Box 79, Folder 18)
  - Subseries III.3. Subject Files
    - CIA--General, 1982-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Country reports--Reagan Administration--Human Rights--Communist countries, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Democracy International booklet, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Environment and Ecology, 1983-1988 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Esche, Dieter (European Network for East-West Dialogue), 1985-1988 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Foreign Policy Research Institute: Conference: “Will the Communist States Survive?”, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Information Requests (made to Helsinki Watch), 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - INS (Immigration and Naturalization Service)--East European cases, 1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - International Citizens Helsinki Watch Conference (Bellagio), 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - International Society for Human Rights: A Position Paper on South Africa, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Peace Movements
      - Background
        - Asia, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
        - Canada, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 12)
          - Peace Magazine, 1985-1986, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
          - Peace Magazine, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
        - Europe, 1982-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
          - Fredsstikka (publication), 1983 (Box 2, Folder 4)
          - Hesse, Dagmar, The West German Peace Movement and New German Nationalism, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - United States
          - Background, 1980-1983, (3 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 6-8)
          - Background: US, 1984-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
            - Pro-Peace, 1985-1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Burlington Peace Coalition, 1980-1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - Campaign for Peace and Democracy, 1982-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
      - Peace and Democracy News, 1984-1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - Disarmament Campaigns (magazine), 1986-1988 (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - Eastern Europe: General, 1982-1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - END (European Nuclear Disarmament), 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 2-3)
        - END: Journal of European Nuclear Disarmament, 1982-1988 (Box 4, Folder 4-5)
      - German Democratic Republic (GDR), 1981-1982, 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Greens--Petra Kelly--German Greens in Bundestag, 1984-1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - HW: From Below: Independent Peace and Environmental Movements in Eastern Europe and the USSR, 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - International Peace Committee and Coordination Center (IPCC), 1986-1988 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - LISTY: Documents of Independent Peace Movements: East-West, 1983-1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - Thompson, E.P., 1980-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
      - Women’s Action for Nuclear Disarmament Education., 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      - World Assembly for Peace and Life Against Nuclear War (Prague), 1983-1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Psychiatry
      - International Association on the Political Use of Psych., 1987 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - United States--involuntary commitment, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Religion under Communism
      - Keston College
        - Frontier (magazine), 1987-1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
        - The Right to Believe, 1980-1985 (Box 6, Folder 6)
        - Keston News Service, 1984-1987, (4 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 7-10)
        - Keston News Service, 1988-1991, (3 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
- Series IV: Janet Fleischmann Files, 1974-1990
  The files contain archival materials related to her work as a Helsinki Watch (HW) and Human Rights Watch (HRW) country researcher for Czechoslovakia, Hungary and Romania. The country files are arranged alphabetically by subject. The files consist of correspondence, manuscripts, memorandums, newspaper clippings, photographs and research reports, and are arranged alphabetically.
  - Czechoslovakia
    - ACTA Quarterly, 1987-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Amnesty International U.S.A., 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - The Charta 77 Foundation--Correspondence, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - The Charta 77 Foundation
      - Correspondence--Janouch, Frantisek, 1985-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - Charta 77 Abstracts, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Charter 77
      - Documents, 1977-1988, (4 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
      - General, 1983, 1987-1988, (2 Folders) (Box 1, Folder 10-11)
      - General, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - General-New York, 1986-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 2, Folder 2-3)
      - International Contacts, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Spokespersons
        - Battek, Rudolf, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
        - Benda, Vaclav, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
        - Dienstbier, Jiri, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 7)
        - Hajek, Jiri, 1979-1989 (Box 2, Folder 8)
        - Havel, Vaclav, 1979-1987 (Box 2, Folder 9)
        - Hejdanek, Ladislav, 1977-1986 (Box 2, Folder 10)
        - Hromadkova, Marie, 1980-1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
        - Kanturkova, Eva, 1981-1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
        - Kozlik, Jan, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
        - Krizkova, Marie Rut, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 14)
        - Kubisova, Marta, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 15)
        - Lis, Ladislav, 1982-1987 (Box 2, Folder 16)
        - Litomisky, Jan, 1983-1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
        - Maly, Vaclav, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 18)
        - Marvanova, Anna, 1982-1986 (Box 2, Folder 19)
        - Palous, Martin, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 20)
        - Palous, Radim, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 21)
        - Patocka, Jan, 1980-1987 (Box 2, Folder 22)
        - Placak, Bedrich, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 23)
        - Rejchrt, Milos, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
        - Ruml, Jiri, 1981-1987 (Box 2, Folder 25)
        - Sabata, Jaroslav, 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
        - Sabatova, Anna, 1984-1987 (Box 2, Folder 27)
        - Silhanova, Libuse, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 28)
        - Stern, Jan, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 29)
        - Sternova, Jana, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 30)
        - Sustrova, Petruska, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 31)
        - Tominova, Zdena, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 32)
        - Vohryzek, Josef, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 33)
        - Spokespersons, 1977-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
      - Statements, 1979-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Tenth Anniversary Evening, 1987 January 26
        - Correspondence, 1987-1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
        - General, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
        - Flanagan, Tommy, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 6)
        - Formanek, Michael, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Children, 1980-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Civic Forum, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Conditions-General, 1977-1986, (2 Folders)
      - General, 1977-1983, undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - General, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence-General, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - CSCE Cultural Forum (Budapest), 1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Cultural Freedom, 1981-1989 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Czechoslovak Newsletter, 1979-1989, (8 Folders) (Box 4, Folder 4-11)
    - “Czechoslovakia ‘88: A Different Seminar” (Prague, 1988 November), 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Demonstrations
      - Wenceslas Square Rally, Prague, 1988 September 24 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - 70th Anniversary of the Founding of Czechoslovakia (1988 October 28), 1988-1889 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - 40th Anniversary of the Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 1988 December 10 (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - “May Day” Demonstration, 1989 May 1 (Box 5, Folder 5)
      - 21st Anniversary of the Soviet Invasion of Czechoslovakia, 1989 August 21 (Box 5, Folder 6)
      - 71st Anniversary of the Founding of Czechoslovakia, 1989 October 28 (Box 5, Folder 7)
      - Jan Opletal Demonstration, 1989 November 17 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Devaty, Stanislav (dissident), 1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Dubcek, Alexander, 1988-1989 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Duray, Miklos, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - East Germany, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Economy, 1987-1989 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Elections-1990 1989-1990 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Emigration--Kubickova, Alena, 1979-1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Environment, 1983-1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Faltus, Anna
      - Update on the Status of Human Rights Activists in Czechoslovakia, 1980-1988, (6 Folders) (Box 6, Folder 2-7)
      - Update on the Status of Human Rights Activists in Czechoslovakia (1988-1989), (4 Folders) (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
    - Foreign Affairs--General, 1980-1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Freedom of Assembly/Association, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Freedom of Expression, 1986-1989 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Freedom of Movement, 1980-1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - General, 1984-1989 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Government, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Government Organized NGOs (GONGO), 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Gypsies, 1978-1988 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Havel, Vaclav, 1987-1990, (2 Folders)
      - General, 1987-1988, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
      - General, 1989-1990 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Helsinki Watch
      - Czechoslovak Helsinki Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Information and Protests, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Human Dimensions of the CSCE, Paris, 1989 May 30-June 23 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Human Rights--Activists--Status
      - General, 1985-1989 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      - Adamek, Josef, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      - Adamek, Frantisek, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      - Bedeiova, Jirina, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - Bednarova, Otta, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - Benda, Marek, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Bila, Renata, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Borovsky, Bronislav, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Bunka, Eduard, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - Burian, Jan, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - Cibulka, Petr, 1978-1989 (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - Dambrowski, Antonin, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - Danhelova, Jitka, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - Danisz, Josef, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - Devaty, Jiri, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - Devaty, Stanislav, 1985-1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Dienstbierova, Zuzana, 1982 (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Dudr, Pavel, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Dus, Jan, 1978-1987 (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - Dvorak, Vaclav, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - Filo, Stanislav, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - Fucik, Vladimir, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - Gabaj, Aloiz, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - Galsky, Desider, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Gans, Jiri, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Gavlas, Tomas, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 28)
      - Gossel, Gabriel, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Gruntorad, Jiri, 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - Hajek, Jan, 1983-1986 (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - Hauptman, Petr, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Havel, Ivan, undated (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Hejlek, Josef, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Helstyn, Dalibor, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Hlozanka, Radim, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - Holecek, Michal, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - Horak, Pavel, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - Horec, Jaromir, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 39)
      - Hrabal, Bohumil, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - Hresko, Michal, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - Ingr, Zdenek, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 42)
      - Jablonicky, Joseph, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 43)
      - Janecek, Jaroslav, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 44)
      - Janik, Bystrik, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 45)
      - Janosikova, Alena, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 46)
      - Javorsky, Stefan, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 47)
      - Jirous, Ivan Martin, 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 48)
      - Jirousova, Vera, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 49)
      - Juhascik, Jan, Jr., 1985 (Box 9, Folder 50)
      - Juhascik, Jan, Sr., 1985 (Box 9, Folder 51)
      - Jung, Josef, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 52)
      - Kania, Walter, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 53)
      - Kantos, Ivo, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 54)
      - Kaplanova, Marie, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 55)
      - Keller, Jan, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 56)
      - Kohout, Milan, 1979-1986 (Box 9, Folder 57)
      - Kohut, Igo, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 58)
      - Kolar, Stanislav, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 59)
      - Konc, Tomas, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 60)
      - Kotrisova, Maria, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 61)
      - Kutrly, Zdenek, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 62)
      - Koutny, Bedrich, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 63)
      - Kozanek, Petr, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 64)
      - Kozdon, Bohumil, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 65)
      - Krivka, Pavel, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 66)
      - Kubicek, Petrn, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - Kubis, Lubomirq, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - Kusy, Miroslav, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - Kuzelova, Kvetoslava, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - Kyncl, Karel, 1981-1987 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - Lacina, Zdenek, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - Machalek, Jakub, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - Marek, Vlastimil, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Matula, Roman, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Mlynarik, Jan, 1981 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Mrtvy, Michal, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - Mucik, Vladimir, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - Mullerova, Lenka (nee, Mareckova), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Navratil, Augustin, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Nechalova, Marie, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Nejedly, Julius, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Nemec, Jaromir, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - Nemec, Jiri, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - Nemeth, Matej, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 19)
      - Nos, Josef, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 20)
      - Novosad, Jaroslav, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 21)
      - Obola, Milan, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 22)
      - Ocenasek, Karel, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 23)
      - Ondrus, Jan, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 24)
      - Pavlicek, Jiri, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 25)
      - Petrivy, Tomas, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 26)
      - Pitas, Stanislav, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 27)
      - Piskor, Jiri, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 28)
      - Pokrupa, Ludek, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 29)
      - Popelka, Jaroslav, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 30)
      - Pospisil, Ctirad, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 31)
      - Prusa, Josef, 1983-1984 (Box 10, Folder 32)
      - Prochazka, Miroslav, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 33)
      - Rohacek, Marek, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 35)
      - Ruml, Jan, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 36)
      - Savrda, Jaromir, 1983-1986 (Box 10, Folder 37)
      - Schubert, Daniel, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      - Seifert, Jaroslav, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 39)
      - Sekaninova-Cakrtova, Gertrude, 1978-1987 (Box 10, Folder 40)
      - Sevec, Ladislav, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 41)
      - Siklova, Jirina, Dr., 1981 (Box 10, Folder 42)
      - Silar, Franktisek, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 43)
      - Silhanova, Libuse, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 44)
      - Simecka, Milan, 1981-1986 (Box 10, Folder 45)
      - Skosnik, Josef, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 46)
      - Skoda, Pavel, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 47)
      - Skuta, Petr 1986 (Box 10, Folder 48)
      - Sobanos, --, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 49)
      - Srp, Karel, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 50)
      - Starek, Frantisek, 1985-1989 (Box 10, Folder 51)
      - Svestka, Jaroslav, 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 52)
      - Trojan, Ladislav, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 53)
      - Uhl, Petr, 1983-1989 (Box 10, Folder 54)
      - Vacek, Eduard, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 55)
      - Vecan, Jan, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 56)
      - Veverka, Otakar, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 57)
      - Vik, Milan, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 58)
      - Vohryzek, Josef, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 59)
      - Wolf, Jiri, 1985-1989 (Box 10, Folder 60)
      - Wonka, Jiri, 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 61)
      - Wonka, Pavel, 1986-1989 (Box 10, Folder 62)
      - Zalesky, Pavel, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 63)
      - Zan, Jan, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 64)
    - Human Rights--Violations, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 65)
    - Hungarian Minority
      - Duray, Miklos, 1980-1985 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - General, 1979-1989 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Husak, Gustav, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Independent Groups
      - “Democratic Initiative”, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - “Independent Initiatives”, 1988-1989 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Independent Movement, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Index on Censorship, 1983-1986 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Information Forum, London, England, 1989 April 18-May 12 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - International Helsinki Federation for Human Rights (IHF), 1989 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Jazz Section of the Czechoslovak Union of Musicians (Jazz Section)
      - General, 1987-1989 (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Petition, 1984-1987 (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Press Clips, 1983-1987 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Trials
        - General, 1984-1986 (Box 12, Folder 2)
        - Jazz Section Trial, 1987 January-December, (2 Folders) (Box 12, Folder 3-4)
      - UNESCO, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Jirous, Ivan (case-dissident), 1985-1989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Kavan, Jan, 1987-1989 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Legislation
      - Background, 1974-1985 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - General, 1986-1990 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Listy: Journal of the Czechoslovak Socialist Opposition, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Missions
      - Czechoslovak, 1980-1982 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Fleischmann, Janet, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Kennedy, David, Esq. (1989 September) (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Labor, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Lawrence, Robert S., MD (1988 January 17), 1987-1988 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Physicians for Human Rights, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Vaclav Havel Trial (Schwartz, Hermann), 1989 February (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - “Movement for Civil Liberties”, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Music, 1987-1989 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Navratil, Augustin, 1988-1989 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Palach, Jan-Commenoration, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Palach Press Limited
      - Correspondence, 1979-1988 (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence--MacArthur Foundation Grant, 1987-1988 (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Infoch Summary of Information on Charter 77 (Nos. 1-24), 1988, (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
      - Infoch Summary of Information on Charter 77, 1988-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 14, Folder 5-6)
      - Infoch Summary of Information on Charter 77, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Summary of Available Documents, No. 7, 1977 July (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Palach Press Bulletin, No. 8, 1977 November (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Summary of Available Documents, No. 8, 1977 November (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Palach press Bulletin, No. 9, 1978 March (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Summary of Available Documents, No. 9, 1978 March (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - Palach Press Bulletin, No. 10, 1978 October (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - Summary of Available Documents, No. 10, 1978 October (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - Limited-Palach Press Bulletin, No. 11, 1979 August (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - Summary of Available Documents, No. 11, 1979 August (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - Palach Press Bulletin, No. 12, 1979 December (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - Summary of Available Documents, No. 12, 1979 December (Box 15, Folder 12)
      - Palach Press Bulletin, No. 13, 1980 April (Box 15, Folder 13)
      - Summary of Available Documents, No. 13, 1980 April (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Palach Press Bulletin and Summary of Available Documents, No. 14, 1980 July (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Palach Press Bulletin (Double Issue), Nos. 15 and 16, 1981 January (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Summary of Available Documents, Nos. 15 and 16, 1981 January (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Palach Press Bulletin and Summary of Available Documents, No. 17, 1981 June (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - palach press bulletin and summary of available documents (S pecial Treble Issue ), Nos. 18, 19 and 20, 1982 April (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Palach Press Bulletin (Treble Issue ), Nos. 21, 22, 23, 1983 February (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - Summary of Available Documents, Nos. 21, 22 and 23, 1984 July (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - Palach Press Bulletin, (Nos. 24-27), 1984-1986, (5 Folders) (Box 16, Folder 3-7)
      - Summary of Available Documents, No. 26, 1986 May (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - Palach Press Bulletin, No. 28/29 (Double Issue), 1987 October (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Peace Movements
      - Charter 77
        - General, 1982-1987, (2 Folders) (Box 17, Folder 1-2)
        - Peace Seminar (1988 June), 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Documents, 1982-1986 (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - General, 1987-1989 (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Independent Peace Movement, 1988-1989 (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Young Art for Peace, 1984-1987 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Pechota, Vratislav, 1979-1982 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Petitions
      - Appeal Proclamation:Just a Few Sentences, 1989 June 29 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Protests, 1989 (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - “Plastic People”, 1981-1989 (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Poland, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Polansky, Ivan (Catholic activist), 1988 (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Political Prisoners, 1987-1989, (2 Folders) (Box 18, Folder 4-5)
      - Political Trials and Arrests, 1986-1989 (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Pospichal, Petr (Catholic activist), 1987-1989 (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Prague Spring
        - 20th Anniversary--Demonstration, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 8)
          - General, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 9)
          - Invasion, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Press Clips, 1979-1988, (5 Folders) (Box 19, Folder 2-6)
    - Press Clips, 1989 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Prisons, 1980-1985, 1987-1990, (3 Folders) (Box 20, Folder 2-4)